Young Master Pan
Isn't this Carpenter Li who went missing not long ago?
What's wrong with him?
He's been poisoned.
Second Master Luo, what are you doing here?
I heard you entered the Miasma Forest.
I was very worried.
So I came to check on you.
Here, let me take him.
A ghost!
Miss Lin, a ghost!
Young Master Pan.
Do you have any more Antidote Pills?
Could you give me some more later?
You still plan to go to that Miasma Forest?
When we wait for Carpenter Li to wake up,
we'll know the whole story.
There's no need for you to take that risk again.
The person I saw in my dream was you.
The one I want to marry is also you.
It is now,
Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
and it will be in the future.
I never thought about marrying and having children before.
Not until I met you.
Only then did I feel that the days to come
could take on other, more hopeful shapes.
A Lan.
Would you be willing to grow old together with me?
Miss A Lan.
You were looking for me?
Yes.
I'd like you to help me inquire
if anyone has heard of the Celestial Frostbloom.
If there's any lead,
I will reward you handsomely.
Alright.
I thought you'd forgotten your mission.
Didn't you say the Celestial Frostbloom
wouldn't die for a while?
What's the rush?
But you haven't even found it yet.
You drew it looking like this monstrosity.
How am I supposed to find it?
The Celestial Frostbloom
just looks like this monstrosity.
Why is A Lan looking for that Celestial Frostbloom?
I'll tell you all later.
By the way,
Has Carpenter Li not woken up yet?
Young Master Pan has already given him medicine.
Whether he can wake up
depends on the next few days.
However,
even if he wakes up,
I'm afraid he won't live for many more days.
Young Master Pan has not yet found
a method to cure the Five-Fold Poison Herb's toxin.
You all go and investigate carefully
Miss Lin's death.
See if there's anything suspicious.
I'm going out for a bit.
You all stay at the Benevolent Peace Hall for now.
Eldest Cousin.
Let me go with you.
No need.
I'll be back soon.
Miss A Lan.
These books here
record all sorts of medicinal herbs
and myths related to the herbs.
Some I haven't even read myself.
See if you can find the one you're looking for,
the Celestial Frostbloom.
Young Master Pan.
You really haven't heard of the Celestial Frostbloom?
Miss A Lan.
Please come outside with me for a moment.
Throughout this entire Tianyin City,
every single white flower
is here.
Take a look.
See if the Celestial Frostbloom you want is here.
You had people gather these?
Yes.
Wasn't it you, miss, who told me to look for them?
Tell me the truth.
Just speak honestly.
It was Young Master Yuwen who gathered them.
He told me not to tell you.
Miss A Lan.
You look first.
I'll go attend to other matters.
Before Young Master Yuwen went out today,
he also took some Antidote Pills from me.
So many flowers.
What a pity, none of them are it.
Isn't that...
This one
is the Celestial Frostbloom.
I didn't expect
him to find it.
He doesn't know
that I'm looking for this Celestial Frostbloom
in order to return.
Stop thinking about all that nonsense.
Can't you see it's about to die?
This is...
Once its petals all fall off,
it will die.
Hurry up and think of a way to save it!
Tell me honestly.
Can this Celestial Frostbloom
cure the Five-Fold Poison Herb's toxin?
Why think so much?
The urgent task is to revive the herb.
Water it or fertilize it?
If it were that simple, would you need to save it?
I know it's not that simple.
So I've figured it out.
Rather than trying aimlessly like this,
I might as well give up completely.
If I can't save it, so be it.
At worst, I'll just stay here.
After all, who knows if the real world
isn't just some storybook novel?
Here,
I am, after all, the dignified Fifth Princess.
You...
Fine.
You win.
But I can only give you one hint.
Far away on the horizon,
yet right before your eyes.
Folk Records of the Strange.
Why did you call me here?
I still have to go with A Zi
to investigate Miss Lin's death.
I want to ask for your help saving this flower.
Why should I help you?
Have you forgotten
you still owe me one thing?
But I don't know how to save it.
I know.
I've carefully gone through this book.
There are indeed a few entries inside
related to medicinal herbs.
Among them,
the stories about herbs gaining sentience are the most plausible.
Herbs gaining sentience is plausible?
Fine, fine, I'll listen to you.
Go on.
How do they gain sentience?
The male lead's tears.
A Lan.
Darn it, you're ruthless.
Hurry up.
This isn't even half a cup yet.
Enough, enough, enough!
Well?
Could it be...
this entry about the water lily transforming into human form?
How did the water lily transform?
Are you deliberately messing with me?
Don't even think about it.
Seventh Cousin!
Let go of my hand.
If you don't agree to my request,
I'll persuade Young Master Pan
to return to the capital with us
and become an Imperial Physician.
I...
You've worked hard.
Seventh Cousin...
I, I, I...
No!
She, she made me do it!
Really, you have to believe me.
It was all A Lan's idea!
Don't look at me like that.
Has Carpenter Li not woken up yet?
All medical texts state
that the Five-Fold Poison Herb is extremely toxic,
but none mention how to cure its poison.
So this is the Five-Fold Poison Herb.
Miss A Lan.
This storage room has a pile of old books.
The second volume of *Folk Records of the Strange* should be among them.
Would you like to take a look?
This lousy book actually has a second volume?
I never expected Tianyin City
to actually have the Five-Fold Poison Herb.
I've only ever seen it in books before.
Miss A Lan.
Young Master Pan.
Your apprentice said that...
said that, um...
the second volume of *Folk Records of the Strange*
is in this storage room.
So I...
came to look for it,
to see if I can find
the method to save the Celestial Frostbloom.
Look, I found it.
Well, Young Master Pan, you carry on with your work.
I'll head out first.
Have you seen Young Master Yuwen?
No.
Miss A Lan.
Wait a moment, please.
You're looking for Young Master Yuwen?
May I ask what it's regarding?
It's like this.
I read in a medical book that
some medicinal herbs react to music.
Since I'm quite skilled at the guqin,
I wanted to ask him to help me find one.
If you see him later,
please pass on the message for me.
Of course, Miss A Lan.
I'm going outside the city to gather herbs.
Remember to give Carpenter Li his medicine.
Yes.
Then I'll be on my way too.
Miss A Lan, you may not know,
but the Five-Fold Poison Herb stains very easily.
You...
Eldest Cousin.
A Zi and I investigated.
The only ones who saw Miss Lin drown
were Second Master Luo and two other townsfolk.
Her funeral
was also arranged by those three.
Aside from Second Master Luo,
the other two are on the missing persons list.
You've just returned.
How is Carpenter Li?
He hasn't woken up.
It's been two days already.
I'm afraid it will be difficult for him to wake up.
And A Lan?
Is she still reading that *Folk Records of the Strange*?
Miss A Lan isn't at the Benevolent Peace Hall right now.
She probably went out.
Oh, right, Young Master.
Miss A Lan told me
that if I saw you,
I should pass on a message for her.
She wants you to help her find a guqin.
With her level of skill,
she'd just be ruining a good instrument.
How exactly did she say it to you?
Tell me word for word.
There's no use struggling, Miss A Lan.
You won't break free
from my silver threads.
She wants to use music to save that wretched flower.
You said Young Master Pan was there too?
My young master
was preparing to gather herbs outside the city at the time.
Young Master, I'll attend to my duties now.
She wouldn't say
she's skilled at the guqin for no reason.
Pan Yu is suspicious.
He took A Lan away.
Where would he take her?
Carpenter Li was found in the Miasma Forest.
The Miasma Forest...
Miss Lin...
There's no need to be surprised, Miss A Lan.
Nowadays, in Tianyin City,
everyone is living well.
Siqing naturally couldn't die before them.
They've all been poisoned by the Five-Fold Poison Herb.
You captured them
to have them test the antidote,
in order to cure Miss Lin's poison.
Miss A Lan, you are truly perceptive.
Young Master Pan practices medicine to save people.
Why seek living people to test the medicine?
For Tianyin City to have its present peace,
it's all thanks to Siqing.
Yet Siqing, because of the vile ones among them,
has been reduced to this state.
If Siqing dies,
I will make the entire Tianyin City perish with her.
What exactly happened
to Miss Lin?
Half a year ago,
a band of mountain bandits came to Tianyin City.
Siqing and I, to save the city's people,
found a way to force those bandits to retreat.
But a few months later,
that band of bandits came again.
That day, I was practicing medicine out of town.
Stop!
Help!
Don't run!
Where do you think you're going?!
Run!
Please, we beg you, show mercy!
Spare our lives, we beg you!
Earlier, several of my brothers
were tricked by you into the Miasma Forest.
We couldn't even find their bodies.
You think I can spare you?!
No, no, no!
It wasn't us!
It was...
It was Miss Lin and her husband!
They're the ones who harmed your brothers!
It was them!
It was that couple!
Miss Lin said she had a way to deal with you.
It was them!
Not us!
It really was them!
Spare us!
Please spare our lives!
Siqing saved them from the bandits' hands.
Yet, to save their own skins,
they handed Siqing over.
Behave!
Let me go!
Sir, behave yourself.
We've brought the person to you.
If it weren't for me,
you'd have died by their blades long ago.
Let me go, sir!
You... you see,
those brothers of yours,
were all killed by her.
It has nothing to do with us!
Yes, yes, yes!
Sir,
we'll vent your anger for you.
Just let us go.
That's right, that's right.
Still trying to run?
Get back here!
This is all your fault!
Run!
You're still running? Where do you think you're going?!
You've doomed us!
It's all your fault!
Run!
You're still running?!
Hit her! Hit her!
Let's see you run now, sir.
We hand her over to you.
She's entirely at your disposal.
Still running?
Hold on.
What a beauty.
Get away!
Get lost!
Don't touch me!
Don't run away!
Get away!
Don't touch me!
Don't run!
Save me!
Please, I beg you, save me!
I'm begging you!
Save me!
Still trying to run?
Sir,
be careful.
Save me! This woman is skilled with poisons.
I beg you!
If you, sir, wish to have some fun,
I can have someone prepare some... stimulating medicine. Save me!
I beg you!
Come here, you!
In the end,
that band of bandits threw Siqing into the Miasma Forest,
into a bottomless pit.
She was injured
and poisoned by the miasma.
She thought her days were numbered.
Who would have guessed
that pit was filled with Five-Fold Poison Herb.
To survive,
she had to eat the Five-Fold Poison Herb.
She endured the agony of the poison daily,
waiting for someone to rescue her.
If I hadn't, two months ago,
developed that Antidote Pill
and come to the Miasma Forest,
accidentally fallen into the pit and found her,
who knows
how much longer she would have had to stay
in that sunless pit.
Second Master Luo and the others, to cover this up,
claimed Miss Lin had perished.
They falsely announced
that Siqing died saving a drowning citizen.
They even held a funeral for her.
Therefore,
you seek revenge for Miss Lin.
Second Master Luo went on a long trip,
temporarily escaping his fate.
However,
he will die sooner or later.
There are six missing citizens in total.
Apart from the two who were with Second Master Luo,
the remaining four citizens
have no connection to this matter.
Young Master Pan,
every grievance has its perpetrator.
Do not implicate the innocent.
Innocent?
If not for Siqing,
Tianyin City would have been a city of the dead long ago.
Their daily joy and happiness
are built upon Siqing's suffering.
She endures the agony of the poison daily.
She doesn't have much time left.
Siqing
You don't need to plead for them.
If you die,
I'll make them all die with you.
No.
A Lan.
Young Master Pan.
Miss Lin wouldn't want you to implicate the innocent.
No.
At this point,
there's no turning back.
They, and Carpenter Li,
are indeed unrelated to Siqing's plight.
But someone has to test the antidote.
It's their fault for entering the Miasma Forest.
And getting lost in illusions, unwilling to wake.
But using innocent people to test the antidote...
Miss Lin might not be happy about it.
I can't worry about that anymore.
As long as I can save Siqing,
I'm willing to do anything.
Siqing.
Are you okay, Siqing? Miss Lin?
Siqing, it's okay.
It's okay, Siqing.
Carpenter Li
was found right here.
If Pan Yu wants to hide someone,
it must be nearby.
Split up and search.
Let's go.
Siqing doesn't have much time left.
I've just developed a new antidote.
Miss A Lan.
You will test it this time.
Young Master Pan.
Calm down.
Listen to me.
I have a way to save Miss Lin.
That Celestial Frostbloom
can cure the Five-Fold Poison Herb's toxin.
What Celestial Frostbloom?
I've never heard of it.
Miss A Lan, don't bother lying to me.
Young Master Pan, I'm not lying.
It's true.
Otherwise, why would I keep...
Young Master Yuwen.
No.
I should address you as Chief Grand Secretary.
I merely wanted Miss A Lan to test an antidote.
You want to test the Five-Fold Poison antidote?
If you dare harm her,
I will make you wish you were dead.
Now that Siqing has little time left,
I have nothing left to fear.
But you, Chief Grand Secretary, are different.
If I apply just a little force,
Miss A Lan will lose her life.
You want to test the antidote?
Let her go.
I'll test it.
Are you sure you want to test it?
Testing an antidote isn't as simple as you think.
At this point, I can only fight poison with poison.
If the antidote works,
everyone will be happy.
If it doesn't work,
the poison will invade the heart meridians.
Death is certain.
Young Master Pan.
Enough talk.
Fine.
Since your mind is made up,
I'll grant your wish.
Chief Grand Secretary.
Proceed.
The antidote... the antidote still doesn't work.
Darn it.
It's all over.
Siqing.
What do I do?
I'm useless.
I still can't save you.
Siqing.
Eldest Brother.
A Lan.
You're awake.
Eldest Cousin.
Where's A Lan?
A Lan is fine.
She just fainted.
What exactly happened?
When we found you and A Lan,
you were both unconscious.
You're still poisoned by the Five-Fold Poison Herb.
About me being poisoned...
don't tell A Lan.
A Lan.
You're awake.
Are you okay?
What on earth happened?
It's a long story.
How did you find me?
So, when Pan Yu was forcing me to test the antidote,
you arrived just in time.
After I arrived,
he fled with Lin Siqing.
Why are you so pale?
Are you alright?
I'm fine.
I just used my inner energy in the Miasma Forest.
It's nothing serious.
Yun Shang of the Shadow Gate.
is the most devoted lover.
Because of Lin Siqing, one thought to be a saint,
another to be a demon.
Yun Shang of the Shadow Gate.
Pan Yu is Yun Shang.
Our purpose for coming south
was to find him.
By the way,
those three commoners who tested the antidote in the cave,
how are they?
They're all at Benevolent Peace Hall.
But they're all poisoned by the Five-Fold Poison Herb.
I'm afraid...
Lin Siqing probably won't live for many more days.
If she dies,
Yun Shang of the Shadow Gate will make the entire Tianyin City
die with her.
Celestial Frostbloom
It might be able to cure the Five-Fold Poison Herb's toxin.
Really.
I'm not entirely sure.
It's just that...
Right now, that Celestial Frostbloom is dying.
I have to find a way to save it.
Send someone to watch Second Master Luo.
Pan Yu is sure to go looking for him.
You rest well.
I'll send people to find Yun Shang of the Shadow Gate.
Eldest Cousin.
Are you alright?
A Lan just said...
The Celestial Frostbloom can cure the poison.
You'll be fine.
This is a poison even Yun Shang of the Shadow Gate can't cure.
No.
There must be a way.
Don't worry about me.
Pan Yu will definitely make another move.
Now that I'm poisoned,
I'm not confident I can subdue him.
If something happens to me,
you take A Lan and the others back to the capital first.
Eldest Cousin...
What nonsense are you saying? I...
No need to say more.
My mind is made up.
I will inform the Shadow Guard of Yuwen Manor.
From now on, you will be their new master.
Eldest Cousin, you...
Don't think about glorifying the ancestors.
Live well according to your own wishes.
Do you hear me?
How are they?
The three newly arrived are not deeply poisoned.
They can hold on for a while longer.
It's just Carpenter Li...
When the poison flared up today,
he couldn't bear the agony.
He nearly bit his tongue to end it.
I'm afraid he doesn't have two days left.
Miss A Lan.
Did the young master really poison them...
to save Miss Lin?
The young master healed the sick in Tianyin City.
He and Miss Lin saved me.
How could he use people to test medicine?
I have something to tell you.
What do you want to tell me?
Before, you said...
you saw in the illusion that our engagement was called off,
and you were very happy about it.
Yes.
I will send a message to His Majesty,
asking him to issue an edict canceling our engagement.
Why bring this up so suddenly?
It's not sudden.
In the cave,
when Pan Yu threatened me with your life,
I didn't feel particularly scared or worried.
So...
You realized...
that you don't actually like me that much.
I understand.
Thank you for telling me.
Maybe it's for the best.
Since Pan Yu is Yun Shang,
why don't we send more people to find him
and force him to reveal the secret on the treasure map?
The Shadow Gate's top disciple,
his martial arts are unfathomable.
Our people are no match for him.
The master's meaning is...
to watch and wait.
Wait until Yuwen Rui
and Yun Shang fight to the death.
Then we'll make our move.